Ing. Roman Ožana / Resume

Hi there,

my name is Roman Ožana. I am a freelance webdesigner and developer with **more than 8 years of experiences**. I'm here to create websites and applications easy to use, intuitive and modern inside. I love tech startups and community around. I enjoy working in small and effective team.

Say hi on Twitter @OzzyCzech

• Address: Prague, Přímětická st.

• Web: www.omdesign.cz

• Email: ozana@omdesign.cz

• Phone: +420 605 783 455



Working Experiences

Testomato s.r.o. – Co-founder & main developer

March 2012 - present

5 years 5 months 20 days

6 years 3 months 21 days

Devel.cz Lab s.r.o. – PHP/JS developer

October 2009 - present

Work as PHP/JS developer and web designer mostly on zdrojak.cz

omdesign.cz - Freelance web designer

8 years 6 months 21 days

October 2009 – present

Freelance web designer and developer of Internet application – mostly in PHP/Javascript.

Former Working Experiences

Intergraph s.r.o. – Application Engineer

9 months

July 2010 - April 2011

Application Engineer (external consultant) – testing of corporate solution for metadata sharing and managing. Developing of simple C# .NET applications.

Skvely.CZ s.r.o. – PHP developer

March 2009 - July 2010

Works there as web application developer mostly in PHP and developing some modules for e-commerce Magento.

Skills & Technologies

Day-to-day comfort

- PHP (up to 7.x)
- OOP, DI, IOC, design patterns
- SQL language
- MySQL, Redis, MongoDB, Memcached
- Javascript ES5 + ES6
- Angular, jQuery
- HTML5, CSS3 (incl. LESS, Sass, cssnext, PostCSS)
- Webpack & Makefile
- Responsive Layout and Design
- Basics of Photoshop CS6 and Adobe Illustrator

Experimnce with

- React, NextJS
- Gulp & Grunt
- Couchbase
- NodeJS

Quality assurance

- E2E testing with Protractor
- Selenium + Selenium IDE
- Unit Testing (PHP Unit, Nette Tester, Mocha)

DevStack

- Docker
- Version Control (GIT)
- Webpack, Makefile
- Travis & GitLab CI
- Linux, MacOS

Languages

- Czech native language
- English communicative

Additional Info

Driving license: B

Education

VŠB – Technical University of Ostrava

2002 - 2007: Geoinformatics

- Study program: Geodesy and cartography, Geoinformatics
- Degree: Master's degree (Msc., Geoingormatics)
- Address: VŠB Technical university of Ostrava, 17.listopadu 15, Ostrava Poruba,
 Faculty of Mining and Geology

SPŠE Rožnov pod Radhoštěm

1997 – 2001: Electronic computer systems

GitHub: https://github.com/OzzyCzech/

StackOverflow: https://meta.stackoverflow.com/users/355316/

Twitter: https://www.twitter.com/OzzyCzech

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/roman.ozana **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/romanozana